

Robin Baumann Computer Vision Engineer



October 08, 1996



Karlsruhe, Germany



robinbaumann.github.io

About me ———

I received my MSc degree with distinction from Karlsruhe University of Applied Sciences, where I specialized in Machine Learning. I am particularly interested in Computer Vision and its intersection with Computer Graphics. I like to spend my free time doing all kinds of sports. For example, I currently prepare for a triathlon. To expand my knowledge, I read non-fiction books about different topics and enjoy spending time outdoors with my friends. My other passion besides sports is music. As such, I play the Saxophone and enjoy going to festivals and concerts.

Skills –

Python

TensorFlow

Python Scientific Stack

PyTorch

Docker

Git

C++

The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).

Education

2019-2021 Karlsruhe University of Applied Sciences

M.Sc. in Computer Science, Final Grade: 1,2 (GPA equivalent: 4,0)

2015-2018 Baden-Württemberg Cooperative State University

B.Sc. in Computer Science. Final Grade: 1,4 (GPA equivalent: 3,7)

Employment History

2021 - today Data Scientist (80 %) inovex GmbH

Mostly Computer Vision Projects

• Image recognition and foreground segmentation.

Research Assistant (20%) Karlsruhe University of Applied Sciences

Continuation of research from Master's thesis

• Effects of data deficiency on shape encoding produced by shape autoencoders used in Neural Fields.

2019 - 2021 Working Student

inovex GmbH

Several Deep Learning and Data Science projects.

• Deep Learning for mobile devices with TensorFlow Lite

2018 - 2019 Big Data Scientist

inovex GmbH

Projects in Deep Learning and Data Engineering.

Circled through many teams in the R&D department.

Point Cloud Classification for iOS Application with TensorFlow

2015 - 2018 Cooperative Student of Computer Science

Projects

2021 Master Thesis inovex GmbH

"Autodecoders for 3D shape completion from deficient 3D input"

• Reconstruction of articulated and non-articulated shapes from single-view depth maps using Neural Occupancy Fields.

2020 Google Summer of Code

TensorFlow

Implemented Mesh R-CNN and Pix3D in TensorFlow Graphics.

2018 **Bachelor Thesis** Testo Visual Systems GmbH

"Classification of reconstructed 3D structures based on object

recognition of facade elements in multiple images"

• Integrate Object Detection CNN into Structure from Motion pipeline

• Fuse semantic information from CNN into 3D reconstruction

Interpersonal Skills

I always try to build rapport with my co-workers. I do so by engaging in discussions and offer to stand by for rubber duck debugging. I always try to lead by example and am a reliable co-worker. One of my strengths is to stay calm and perform consistently in stressful projects and prior to deadlines.

